After the Fall from Innocence the Legend begins.
Legends of the Fall is a drama, western, romance film directed by Edward Zwick.
In early 20th-century Montana, Col.
William Ludlow lives on a ranch in the wilderness with
his sons, Alfred, Tristan, and Samuel.
Eventually, the unconventional but close-knit family are bound by loyalty, tested by war, and
torn apart by love, as told over the course of several decades in this epic saga.
Tristan Ludlow, played by Brad Pitt.
Col. William Ludlow, played by Anthony Hopkins.
Alfred Ludlow, played by Aidan Quinn.
Susannah Fincannon Ludlow, played by Julia Ormond.
Samuel Ludlow, played by Henry Thomas.
Isabel Two Decker Ludlow, played by Karina Lombard.
Legends of the Fall is a 1994 American epic historical Western drama film directed by Edward Zwick,
and starring Brad Pitt, Anthony Hopkins, Aidan Quinn, Julia Ormond and Henry Thomas.
Based on the 1979 novella of the same title by Jim Harrison, the film is about three brothers and their father living in the
wilderness and plains of Montana in the early 20th century and how their lives are affected by nature, history, war, and love.
The film's timeframe spans nearly 50 years from the early 20th century; World War I,
through the Prohibition era, and ending with a brief scene set in 1963.
The film was nominated for three Academy Awards and won
for Best Cinematography (John Toll).
Both the film and book contain occasional Cornish language
terms, the Ludlows being a Cornish immigrant family.
The film explores themes of sibling relationship, post-traumatic stress disorder
(ptsd), based on novel or book, world war i, journey around the world.
The tone is emotional.